Guide to the Seward Collins Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1920-52; Series I; 5.25; (13 boxes)
  - "Ra-Ric" general, 1928-39 (Box 9, Folder 263-64)
  - "Rig-Ry" general, 1922-37 (Box 10, Folder 265-66)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, 1930-45 (Box 10, Folder 267)
  - Ransom, Richard B., 1935-36 (Box 10, Folder 268)
  - Rascoe, Burton, 1925-33, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 269-70)
    See also: Box 21, folder 569
  - Reilly, Joseph J., 1931-33 (Box 10, Folder 271)
  - Repplier, Agnes, 1930-33 (Box 10, Folder 272)
  - Rhine, J. B., 1937 (Box 10, Folder 273)
  - Rice, Philip B., 1929 (Box 10, Folder 274)
  - Richardson, Eudora Ramsey, 1930-36 (Box 10, Folder 275)
  - Rogers, Bruce, 1929-32 (Box 10, Folder 276)
  - Rumford, Press, 1927-28 (Box 10, Folder 277)
  - "S" general, 1922-39 (Box 10, Folder 278-85)
  - Sackville-West, Vita, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 286)
  - Sagendorph, Robb, 1932-34 (Box 10, Folder 287)
  - Salpeter, Harry, 1930-31 (Box 10, Folder 288)
  - Salter, W. H. (Mrs.), 1933 (Box 10, Folder 289)
  - Sanders, L. W., 1927-28 (Box 11, Folder 290)
  - Sanger, Margaret, 1924-30 (Box 11, Folder 291)
  - Sargent, Porter, 1930-41 (Box 11, Folder 292)
  - Schneider, Isidor, 1932-36, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 293)
  - Seldes, Amanda & Gilbert, 1925-30 (Box 11, Folder 294)
  - The Sewanee Review
    See: William S. Knickerbocker
  - Shafer, Robert, 1929-35, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 295-98)
    See also: Box 11, folder 300
  - Shafer-Tate Controversy, 1929-30 (Box 11, Folder 299)
  - Sheed, Maisie, 1935-43 (Box 11, Folder 300)
  - Shepard, Odell, 1930-31 (Box 11, Folder 301)
  - Sidgwick, [Eleanor Balfour] (Mrs. [Henry] Sidgwick), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 302)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1927-34 (Box 11, Folder 303-07)
    See also: Box 10, folder 277
  - The Southern Review
    See: Cleanth Brooks Robert Penn Warren
  - Stallings, Laurence, 1927 Nov 21 (Box 11, Folder 308)
  - Starkie, Enid, 1951-52 (Box 11, Folder 309)
  - Starrett, Vincent, 1928-33 (Box 11, Folder 310)
  - Stockbridge, Frank Parker, 1930-31 (Box 11, Folder 311)
  - Stoddard, Lothrop, 1933-35 (Box 11, Folder 312)
  - Stone, I. F., 1939-40 (Box 11, Folder 313)
  - Styron, Arthur, 1934-35 (Box 11, Folder 314)
  - Suckow, Ruth, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 315)
  - "T" general, 1928-40 (Box 11, Folder 316-18)
  - Tapley, Roberts, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 319)
  - Tate, Allen, 1928-37 (Box 12, Folder 320-25)
  - Tate, Caroline Gordon (Mrs. Allen Tate), 1933, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 326)
  - Teall, Dorothy, 1930-32 (Box 12, Folder 327)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1934 Mar 15 (Box 12, Folder 328)
  - Thompson, Alan Reynolds, 1929-34 (Box 12, Folder 329)
  - Thompson, Dorothy, 1936-37 (Box 12, Folder 330)
  - "U" general, 1927-33 (Box 12, Folder 331)
  - "V" general, 1928-40 (Box 12, Folder 332)
  - Vanderbilt University--Department of English
    See: Donald Davidson, Box 4 folder 112; Frank L. Owsley, Box 9 folder 250; John Crowe Ransom, Box 10 folder 267
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1922, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 333)
  - "W" general, 1927-39 (Box 12, Folder 334-38)
  - Wallace, DeWitt, 1930-32 (Box 12, Folder 339)
  - Walt Disney Productions, Ltd., 1934 May 18 (Box 12, Folder 340)
  - Walton, Edna Lou, 1931-32 (Box 12, Folder 341)
  - Warner, Langdon, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 342)
  - Warren, Austin, 1929-37, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 343-45)
  - Warren, Dale, 1928-34, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 346)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1933-36 (Box 13, Folder 347)
  - Watt, John Y., 1931-35 (Box 13, Folder 348)
  - Welty, Eudora, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 349)
  - West, Rebecca, 1928-30 (Box 13, Folder 350)
  - Williams, Michael, 1930-41 (Box 13, Folder 351)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1922-52 (Box 13, Folder 352)
  - Winchell, Walter, 1929, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 353)
  - Winters, Yvor, 1932-37 (Box 13, Folder 354)
  - Woodlock, Thomas F., 1933-38, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 355)
  - Woolf, Virginia, 1930 Mar 11 (Box 13, Folder 356)
  - "Y" general, 1927-33 (Box 13, Folder 357)
  - Yale University Press
    See: Norman V. Donaldson, Box 5 folder 124
  - "Z" general, 1929-33 (Box 13, Folder 358)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1924-33, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 359)
- Subject Files, 1918-39; Series II; 2; (5 boxes)
  Series II, Subject Files, is alphabetically arranged.
  - Adams, Paul, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 360)
  - Agrarianism, 1933, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 361)
  - Aldington, Richard, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 362)
  - The American Review, 1933-37 (Box 14, Folder 363-69)
  - The American Review Book Shop, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 370)
  - Arata, Oliver, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 371)
  - Babbitt, Irving, 1920-29, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 372-76)
  - Barr, Donald, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 377)
  - Bazin, René, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 378)
  - Beals, Carleton, 1939, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 379)
  - Belloc, Hilaire, 1935, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 380-81)
  - Benchley, Robert C., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 382)
  - Benjamin, José, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 383)
  - Binsee, Harry Lorin, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 384)
  - Blake, Howard, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 385)
  - Blyton, W. J., 1935 (Box 15, Folder 386)
  - The Bookman, 1929-33 (Box 15, Folder 387-88)
  - The Bookman succeeded by The American Review, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 389)
  - Brooks, Cleanth, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 390)
  - Buchanan, Annabel Morris, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 391)
  - Burke, Armand Joseph (Box 15, Folder 392)
  - Burke, Thomas, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 393)
  - Burman, Ben Lucien, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 394)
  - Bush, Douglas, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 395)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1924-29 (Box 15, Folder 396)
  - Cabell, James Branch, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 397)
  - Calverton, V. F., 1936 (Box 15, Folder 398)
  - Caponigri, Aloysius R., 1934 (Box 15, Folder 399)
  - Chamberlain, John R., 1932 (Box 15, Folder 400)
  - Chapman, John Jay, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 401)
  - Chesterton, G. K., 1930-36, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 402)
  - Chilom, Eleanor Carroll, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 403)
  - Clark, Harry Hayden, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 404)
  - Cleveland, Richard F., 1933 (Box 15, Folder 405)
  - Colby, Nathalie Sedgwick, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 406)
  - College of the Sacred Heart, New York City, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 407)
  - Cram, Ralph Adams, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 408)
  - Crowninshield, Frank, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 409)
  - Davidson, Donald (Box 16, Folder 410)
  - Davis, William Stearns, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 411)
  - de Valera, Eamon, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 412)
  - Distributionism, 1933-36 (Box 16, Folder 413)
  - Dow, Dorothy, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 414)
  - Edmonds, Walter D. (Box 16, Folder 415)
  - Eliot, T. S., 1929, 1934, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 416)
  - Elliott, G. R., 1928, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 417)
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1928, 1932, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 418)
  - England, Robert A., 1933-35 (Box 16, Folder 419)
  - Ernst, Morris, 1928-29 (Box 16, Folder 420)
  - Fascism, 1933-35 (Box 16, Folder 421)
  - Flandran, Grace, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 422)
  - Fletcher, John Gould, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 423)
  - Fodor, Nandor (Box 16, Folder 424)
  - Foerster, Norman, 1923-34 (Box 16, Folder 425)
  - Follett, Wilson, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 426)
  - Ford, Ford Madox, 1927, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 427)
  - Gass, Sherlock Bronson, 1928-32 (Box 16, Folder 428)
  - Gill, Eric, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 429)
  - Goldsmith, Sophie L., 1931 (Box 16, Folder 430)
  - Goodrich, Marcus, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 431)
  - Griebl Nazi Spy Case, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 432)
    See: Box 11, folder 313
  - Guinnard, A. (Mme), 1935 (Box 16, Folder 433)
  - Hagy, Nan, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 434)
  - Hall, T. Proctor, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 435)
  - Hapgood, Norman, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 436)
  - Hard, William, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 437)
  - Hatch, Richard, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 438)
  - Haviland-Taylor, Katherine, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 439)
  - Hawthorne, Hildegarde, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 440)
  - Hawthorne, Julian, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 441)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 442)
  - Henry, Alice, 1928-29 (Box 16, Folder 443)
  - Hillyer, Robert, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 444)
  - Hook, Sidney, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 445)
  - Hubbard, Wynant Davis, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 446)
  - Hughes, Richard, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 447)
  - Hughes, Rupert, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 448)
  - Humanism, 1929-35 (Box 16, Folder 449)
  - Hunter, Rex, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 450)
  - Ingalls, Eleanor C., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 451)
  - James, Norah, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 452)
  - James, Stanley B., 1935 (Box 16, Folder 453)
  - Jules-Bois, H. A., 1936-37 (Box 16, Folder 454)
  - Kelly, John Eoghan, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 455)
  - Kendrick, Benjamin, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 456)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 457)
  - Kuo, Ping-Ho, 1929-30 (Box 16, Folder 458)
  - Lewis, Wyndham (Box 17, Folder 459)
  - Liberty Bonds: advertisement, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 460)
  - Little, Richard Henry, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 461)
  - Lobagola, Bata Kindai Amgoza Ibn, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 462)
  - Lyon, Sylvia, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 463)
  - McGrady, Pat, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 464)
  - Macleod, Norman, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 465)
  - Macy, John, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 466)
  - Maloney, William J., 1937 (Box 17, Folder 467)
  - Mann, Dorothea Lawrance (Box 17, Folder 468)
  - Marks, Laura Hechinger, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 469)
  - Masefield, John, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 470)
  - Mei, K. T., 1931 (Box 17, Folder 471)
  - Menut, Albert, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 472)
  - Mercantile Library, Cincinnati, Ohio: centennial celebration, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 473)
  - Millar, Moorehouse F. X., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 474)
  - Monarchism, 1933-34 (Box 17, Folder 475)
  - More, Paul Elmer, 1919-30, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 476-79)
  - Mumford, Lewis, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 480)
  - Munson, Gorham B., 1930, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 481-84)
  - Murray, J. Middleton, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 485)
  - The New School for Social Research, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 486)
  - Nickerson, Hoffman, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 487)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1930-39 (Box 17, Folder 488)
  - Owsley, Frank L., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 489)
  - Parker, Dorothy, 1927-30 (Box 17, Folder 490)
  - Parry, Albert, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 491)
  - Paul, Camille Haynes, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 492)
  - Pearce, Helen, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 493)
  - Pearson, Edmund, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 494)
  - Peck, Harry Thurston, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 495)
  - Pell, Herbert C., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 496)
  - Penty, A. J., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 497)
  - Phillpotts, Eden, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 498)
  - Prescott, Charlotte Hubbard, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 499)
  - Priestley, J. B., 1931 (Box 18, Folder 500)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 501)
  - Rascoe, Burton, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 502)
  - Richardson, Eudora Ramsay, 1928-36 (Box 18, Folder 503)
  - Richardson, Henry Handel (Box 18, Folder 504)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton, 1928-31 (Box 18, Folder 505)
  - Rolvaag, O. E., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 506)
  - Russell, Bertrand (Box 18, Folder 507)
  - Sackville-West, Vita, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 508)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 509)
  - Scottsboro Case, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 510)
  - Senske, A. C., 1927 (Box 18, Folder 511)
  - Shafer, Robert, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 512-13)
  - Sherman, Stuart P., 1917 (Box 18, Folder 514)
  - Shuford, Thomas Rhyne, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 515)
  - Silver, Abba Hillel, 1934 Mar 18 (Box 18, Folder 516)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1932, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 517)
  - Spain, 1918-38 (Box 18, Folder 518-19)
    See also: Box 21, folder 570
  - Starrett, Vincent, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 520)
  - Steele, William L., 1935 (Box 18, Folder 521)
  - Sulkie, Thomas, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 522)
  - Taggard, Genevieve, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 523)
  - Tapley, Roberts, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 524)
  - Tate, Allen, 1928, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 525)
  - Van Aver, Albert, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 526)
  - Vollert, Cyril O., 1935 (Box 18, Folder 527)
  - Ward, Leo, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 528)
  - Warren, Austin, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 529)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 530)
  - Warren, Schuyler N., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 531)
  - Weaver, Raymond, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 532)
  - Wecter, Dixon, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 533)
  - Wells, Gabriel, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 534)
  - Wells, H. G., 1927, 1931, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 535)
  - West, Rebecca, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 536)
  - Williams, Morris H., 1922 (Box 18, Folder 537)
  - Winslow, Thyra Samter, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 538)
  - Wood, Albert, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 539)
  - Woodlock, Thomas F., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 540)
  - Young, Stark, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 541)
- Business Papers, 1927-37; Series III; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series III, Business Papers, is arranged by subject in relative order of importance.
  See also: Box 21, folders 571-75
  - History of The Bookman, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 542)
  - History of The American Review, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 543)
  - Policy statements, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 544)
  - Business records, 1928-32, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 545)
  - Legal matters, 1928-34 (Box 19, Folder 546)
  - Office files of Seward Collins: list of contents, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 547)
  - Circulation and subscription material, 1927-35 (Box 19, Folder 548)
  - Articles on authors, 1927-31 (Box 19, Folder 549)
  - Portraits and caricatures, Lists of (Box 19, Folder 550)
  - Censorship, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 551)
  - Sample stationery, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 552)
  - Publicity, 1929-34 (Box 19, Folder 553)
  - Graphics, 1929, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 554)
  - Advertisements: rates, quotes, statements, etc., 1927 (Box 19, Folder 555)
  - Advertisements: proofs, 1920s-30s (Box 19, Folder 556)
  - Advertisements, 1920s-30s (Box 19, Folder 557)
- Other Papers, 1922-52; Series IV; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series IV, Other Papers, is divided into three sections, Writings, Personal Papers, and Printed Works. Each section is alphabetically arranged.
  - WRITINGS
    - "The Eagle Eye", 1922 (Box 20, Folder 558)
    - "King of Columnists", ca. 1920 (Box 20, Folder 559)
    - "Personal", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 560)
    - Poems, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 561)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Biographical information, 1927-52 (Box 20, Folder 562)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 563)
    - Papers, Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 564)
  - PRINTED WORKS
    See also: Box 21, folders 576-80
    - Anticomintern, 1937-Oct 24 (Box 20, Folder 565)
    - The Atlantic Bookshelf, 1929 Sep (Box 20, Folder 566)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1943 Aug (Box 20, Folder 567)
    - The New South, 1937-38 (Box 20, Folder 568)
- Oversize, 1919-38; 1.5; (1 box)
  The Oversize material contains papers from Series II, III, and IV and is arranged in the same order as material in those series.
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - Rascoe, Burton, n.d. (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 569)
    - Spain, 1919 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 570)
  - BUSINESS PAPERS
    - Business records, n.d. (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 571)
    - Galley proofs, n.d. (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 572)
    - Advertisements: galley proofs, n.d. (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 573)
    - Advertisements: proofs, n.d. (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 574)
    - Advertisements, 1920s-30s (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 575)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Collier's (pp. 21-24, 43-48), 1928 Mar 3 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 576)
    - G.K.'s Weekly, 1938 Mar 10 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 577)
    - John O'London's Weekly, 1931 Jul 4 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 578)
    - The Saturday Review, 1927 Nov 26 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 579)
    - The Saturday Review, 1928 Oct 6 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 580)